Register of the Paul Haensel (Pavel Petrovich Genzel') Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1923-1949
  - "Fish as a Food Savior,"., 1946 May 21 (Folder 7: 19)
  - "The Grain Problem,"., 1946 May 21 (Folder 7: 20)
  - "Russians Want Periodicals," Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1946 May 30 (Folder 7: 21)
    Holograph and printed copy. Includes background materials
  - Letter to the editor, Miami Daily News, 1946 June 1 (Folder 7: 22)
    Clipping and correspondence, 1946
  - "Our Relations with Russia," talk before the Evanston Group Whitehouse?, 1946 June 18 (Folder 7: 23)
  - "The Truth About Tsarist Russia," talk before the Young People's Club of Holy Trinity Cathedral, 1946 July 16 (Folder 7: 24)
  - "Kogo vybirat'?" Russkaia zhizn', 1946 October 26-31 (Folder 7: 25)
  - "A Plan for Immediate Tax Measures," The Bulletin of the National Tax Association, 1947 March (Folder 7: 26)
    Typescript and printed copy. Includes correspondence regarding publication
  - "Novyi poklep na tsarskuiu Rossiiu," Russkaia zhizn', 1947 March 8 (Folder 7: 27)
  - "Vodka i sov. Diplomatiia," Russkaia zhizn', 1945 April 9 (Folder 7: 28)
    Printed copy. Includes letter from A. Gramotov, 1947 April 24
  - "Pravovoe polozhenie russkoi zhenshchiny,"., 1947 July 1 (Folder 7: 29)
  - "Shakespeare's Will," letter to the editor, Washington Post, 1947 January 19, Chicago Daily Tribune, 1947 June 3, Chicago Sunday Tribune (entitled "Shakespeare's Second-Best Bed"), 1947 June 22 (Folder 7: 30)
    Holograph and printed copies
  - "V staroi Rossii byla svoboda!" Russkaia zhizn', 1947 June 24 (Folder 7: 31)
  - "K iskhodu vyborov," Russkaia zhizn', 1949 February 2 (Folder 7: 32)
    Printed copy (incomplete)
- COURSE MATERIALS, 1907-1948
  Consists of notes, clippings, syllabi and related matter. May include materials for publications and subject materials not necessarily used in lectures
  - Moscow University, 1907-1908-- "Istoriia razvitiia finansovogo khoziaistva i noveishaia finansovaia politika na zapadie." Lectures (Folder 7: 33)
  - Moscow University, 1907-1908-- "Istoriia razvitiia finansovogo khoziaistva i noveishaia finansovaia politika na zapadie." Lectures (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Northwestern University and Mary Washington College, 1933-1948
    - "Comparative Public Finance,"., 1933 (Folder 8: 2)
      Lectures
    - "Elements of Public Finance"
      - Syllabi, 1933-1942 (Folder 8: 3)
      - Material for lectures, 1940-1946 (Folder 8: 4-6)
    - "Modern International Economic Problems"/"Modern Economic History" (Box 9)
      - Syllabi, 1937-1941 (Folder 9: 1)
      - Material for lectures, 1936-1948
        - General (Folder 9: 2-3)
        - Great Britain (Folder 9: 4-5)
        - France (Box-folder 10: 1-3)
        - Germany (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
        - Italy (Folder 11: 3-4)
        - Soviet Union.
          See [Soviet Economics and Government]
    - "Public Budgets" (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - [Soviet Economics and Government]
      - Syllabus, c.1942-1943 (Folder 12: 2)
      - Material for lectures, 1937-1948 (Folder 12: 3-4)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1934-1948 (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
  Mainly clippings; some brochures and leaflets. May also include materials intended for lectures. Subjects include economics, finance, international trade, taxation, Russian history, emigration (particularly from Russia and the USSR)
- PRINTED MATTER (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1909-1943 (Folder 14: 4)
  Fourteen photographs of Paul Haensel by himself and with his wife Nina, son Vladimir, and unidentified figures. Not filmed